Dan Hough

Full-stack mobile and web developer



About Dan

I'm a London-based software engineer working in Huddle's Mobile team. I spend a lot of my time working on web applications, as well as native iOS Applications. I am comfortable going up and down the stack in order to implement a new feature. I have more than 4 years developing software professionally, and I am keen to learn more and extend my skills in programming as well as product management.

Lists of Things

Hobbies: Bouldering, Squash, Snowboarding, Running. Illlustration & drawing, design. Singing, guitar & songwriting. Music. Public speaking. Cinema, television, coffee, general Internetting.

Recent Books: Joel on Software by Joel Spolsky, JavaScript: The Good Parts by Douglas Crockford, The Newsflesh Trilogy by Mira Grant, Rework by 37signals, You Talkin' to Me? by Sam Leith.

Side Projects & Cool Stuff I've Made:

StreetScout (http://streetscoutapp.com)
SkiFree.js (http://basicallydan.github.io/skifree.js)
Busking (http://youtu.be/LmDXpLbi2w0)
ONDA (https://github.com/basicallydan/Onda)

Windows or Mac? Happy with both.

Employment History

Huddle

Junior Developer to Developer, July 2011 - Present

Worked on a backend REST API (.NET), frontend single-page web app using **Knockout.js** and a custom JS module manager, used by thousands of users daily. Helped refactor a legacy system into a much more **scalable SOA** system. Led a prototype skunkworks team. Joined mobile team to work on native iOS apps. Agile methodology: **SCRUM** teams, daily **standups**, estimations, elaborations & retrospectives.

Thin Martian

Intern to Developer, July 2010 - July 2011

Backend and frontend for clients' websites and microsites using mostly .NET and JavaScript.

Formal Education & Training

The University of Sheffield

September 2006 - June 2010

1st Class BEng Software Engineering

Akeley Wood Senior School

December 2001 - June 2006

A-Levels: Business Studies A, Computing A, Psychology C

GCSEs: 1 A, 4 Bs, 4 Cs

Technical Skills

Experience	
JavaScript	Hero
Node.js	
Objective-C	
РНР	
C#	
Recency	
Never JavaScript	This week
Node.js	
Objective-C	_
РНР	
C#	

Other Programming Languages & Technologies

Java, Python, PHP, MongoDB, SQL, CSS, SASS, LESS, (X)HTML (inc. HTML5), Rake, Grunt, XML, Pascal, Haskell, PROLOG.

Software

Sublime Text, Git, Visual Studio, XCode, Adobe Photoshop, Flash & Illustrator (CS1-CS5), Mac OS X, MS Windows (ME - 7), Linux (openSuSE and Ubuntu), SVN, Eclipse.

Software Engineering Concepts

Agile Methodologies, Object-oriented Design, REST, Test-Driven Design, Continuous Integration, Behaviour-Driven Design, Coincidence-Driven Design, SOA, MVC, MVVM, AJAX, Modular Design, Event-driven programming.

In this Curriculum Vitae I have attempted to include only the most relevant information for readability and brevity. However, if you have any further questions about my experience or skills please feel free to email me at daniel.hough@gmail.com or see my personal website danhough.com:)